Erik Hoffman

https://erikhoffman.ca

Address: Aurora, Ontario | Home Phone#: 1-289-383-4992 | Email: erik hoffman@outlook.com

WORK OBJECTIVE

To find a position that allows me to use my strong background in computer science and software engineering skills to work on innovative technologies and modern applications.

In combination with these core credentials I would apply my well developed team working abilities gleaned from both my work and school experience in software development life cycles. I believe that a foundation built on a perfect balance between critical thinking and communication with your team are imperative for creating successful projects.

QUALIFICATIONS

- → Multiple years of programming in C, Python, Java, HTML, CSS, Javascript/EcmaScript, Typescript
- → Strong skills in frontend frameworks; Angular2, AngularJS and React as well as some jsp for legacy systems
- → Strong skills in ExpressJS and Java backends as well as microservice paradigms
- → Intermediate skills in Amazon Web Services and Microsoft Azure
- → Focus on test-driven development (JUnit, Jasmine, Karma) to ensure business logic is not broken by new code
- → Linux/Windows command line, bash scripts to automate tasks and improve work speed
- → Git and SVN experience in a professional, multi-project setting
- → Knowledge of Jenkins, Jira, Bitbucket, Confluence, Trello
- → Writing of technical documents, deployment instructions and tutorials whenever I feel they are helpful

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF GUELPH

Guelph, ON

Bachelor of Computing Honours (B.Comp)

Computer Science Major, Mathematics Minor

Fall 2012 - Fall 2016

Notable Courses Completed: Data Structures, Networking and Web Development, Operating Systems, Discrete Mathematics, Combinatorics and Graph Theory, Algorithms, Security (RSA and prime mathematics), Microprocessors and Assembly Language, Theory of Computation, Databases, Artificial Intelligence, File Storage Structures and Data Retrieval.

BRADFORD DISTRICT HIGH SCHOOL

Bradford, ON

Fall 2007 - June 2011

Took Computer Science courses starting in grade 10, Ontario Scholar all 4 years

WORK EXPERIENCE

SMART SOLUTION

Aurora, ON

Web Developer (Full Stack)

April 2019 - Present

- → Wrote full stack solutions for an industry leading banking platform and member-facing applications
- → Used new tech such as Ionic and Angular 2+/VueJS and maintained legacy Java projects in Spring/Springboot
- ightarrow Gave talks to entire team on upgrading tech stacks and paradigms in order to improve workflow
- ightarrow Performed BA role by writing every use case for a modern mobile banking app replacement
- → Worked with business and design team to develop the most client-friendly solutions for features and bug fixes

CANADIAN IMPERIAL BANK OF COMMERCE (CIBC)

Toronto, ON

Intermediate Applications Developer

January 2017 - April 2019

- → Wrote full stack solutions for a client-facing application in AngularJS, ExpressJS, Jasmine, Java Spring
- ightarrow Part of agile development team, using Jira, Bitbucket and Confluence for workflow
- Wrote deployment scripts in Jenkins and wrote technical documents on how to maintain environments

UNIVERSITY OF GUELPH

Guelph, ON

Teaching Assistant for Introduction to Computing

September 2016 - December 2016

- → Assist students with learning basics of applications: Word, Excel, Powerpoint and Access, Javascript
- ightarrow Conducted office hours, answered student questions at any time and graded assignments